Guide to the James A. Healy Collection of Irish literature, 1870-1976
Department of Special Collections
- CATALOGUE OF MANUSCRIPT, BOXES 1-16
  - CONOR, WILLIAM (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Conor, William (Belfast) to JAH, 10-22-38., ALS - 2
    - Clippings re Conor's death, article from Ulster Commentary
  - CONTEMPORARY POETRY MAGAZINE (Box 4, Folder 47)
    The following letters are all from Mary Owings Miller, the editor in Baltimore, to OG:
    - 12-8-41., TLS - 1
    - 1-31-42., TLS - 3 w/cov forwarding it to JAH by OG
    - 2-10-42., TLS - 1, enc. TS of her poem O St. J. G, w/cov.
    - 5-4-42., TLS - 1
    - 5-7-42., TLS - 1
    - 10-15-42., TLS -2
    - 5-10-43., TLS - 1
    - 10-31-43., TLS -1
    - 11-22-43., APCS -1
    - 12-8-43., TLS - 1
    - 12-19-43., TLS - 1
    - 1-30-44 (1st letter)., TLS - 1
    - 1-30-44 (2nd letter)., TLS 1
    - 2-26-44., TLS - 1
    - 3-24-44., TLS - 1
    - 3-30-44., TLS - 1
    - 4-9-44., TLS - 1
    - 4-12-44., TLS - 1
    - 6-19-44., TLS - 1
    - 6-21-44., TLS - 1
      The following letters are from Mary Owings Miller to JAH:
    - 3-27-42., TLS - 1
    - 1-30-44., TLS - 1
    - 3-2-44., TLS - 1
    - 3-8-44., TLS - 1
    - 5-15-44., TLS - 1
    - 10-7-44. Bill, TD w/a - 1
    - 11-21-44., TLS - 1
    - 12-29-44., APCS - 1
    - 5-4-43to Sister Mary Marguerite., TLc - 1
  - CORKERY, DANIEL (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Corkery, Daniel (Cork) to EAB, ND., ALS - 1
    - [Signed Corcora] (Cork) to [Joseph Campbell], 1-8-34., ALS - 1
  - CUALA PRESS: INVOICES (Box 4, Folder 49)
    Ca. 80 invoices and some covers, customs labels, notes, etc. 1938-53
  - CUALA PRESS: LISTS ETC. (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - List of Dun Emer and CP books, signed by ECY, 8-12-37., AD - 2
    - List of books w/a by ECY, 5-18-38., AD - 1
    - Typed list of greeting cards [1938]., TD - 5
    - [ECY], list of bookshops etc, [1939]., TD - 3
    - Statement of JAH's account with CP [6-1-40]., TD - 1 w/cov.
    - Statement of JAH's account, 4-10-46., TDc - 2
    - Statement of JAH's account, 8-31-46., TDc - 1
    - List of books delivered to C. Neenan, 9-28-48., TD - 1
    - JAH'S order to CP, 2-1-50., TD - 2
    - CP books bought by JAH, 1943-50 [1950?]., AD - 6 [in GY's hand]
    - List of Cards etc. impossible to get now, ND., TD - 4 1/2
    - List of DE and CP books, ND., TD - 2
    - ECY set `wants' list, ND., TD - 1
    - JAH Cuala account list, ND., AD - 1
    - List of books for sale by ECY, ND., TD - 1
    - Purchases from CP, ND., TD - 1
    - 2 empty covers to JAH; 1 to Patrick McCartan
  - CUALA PRESS: REFERENCE MATERIAL ON (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Printed Memorandum... of Cuala Industries Ltd., 10-6-38., Booklet, 16 pp. w/cov.
    - [No author], untitled article on CP, 1952., TDc and pc - 6
    - Lochlin MacGlynn, In the Golden Land of Yeats. Clipping from The Irish Press, 5-23-46 -, 1 (12)
    - CP and PC, clipping re, 10-6-69
    - E. C. Marriner, 50 Years of the CP, 5-1-53., TDc - 23
    - R.M. Fox, Triumph of CP, from Irish Digest (Oct. 1953) -, 3
    - Irish University Press's flyer for reprinted CP books, 1970 -, 4
  - CUALA PRESS: EXHIBITION AT COLBY COLLEGE (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Announcements of 50th Anniversary Exhibition of CP, 1903-53, (4)
    - Story on exhibit [1953]., TD - 2
    - Photos of exhibit -, 6
    - Clippings -, 6
  - CULLINAN, EUSTACE (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Cullinan, Eustace (NP) to OG, 11-29-32., TLc - 2
  - CULLINAN, J.S. (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Cullinan, J.S. (Houston) to RC, 4-29-24., TLS - 2
    - Shephards, R.A. (for Cullinan) (Houston) to RC, 8-11-25., TLS - 2
    - Shephards, R.A. (for Cullinan) (Houston) to RC, 10-20-25., TLS - 1
    - Cullinan, J.S. (Houston) to RC, 11-10-25., TLc - 4
    - Cullinan, J.S. (Houston) to RC, 4-14-26., TLS - 2
    - Cullinan, J.S. (Houston) to RC, 12-27-28., TLS - 2
    - Cullinan, J.S. (Houston) to RC, 3-12-29., TLS - 2
    - Cullinan, J.S. (Houston) to OG, 6-16-30., TLc - 2
    - Cullinan, J.S. (Houston) to RC, 7-18-34., TLS - 2
    - [Cullinan, J.S.] (Houston) to RC, 8-31-35., TLS - 2
    - Cullinan, J.S. (Houston) to RC, 10-5-35., TLS - 2
  - CUSHING, CARDINAL (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Cushing, Cardinal Richard (B) to JAH Foundation Inc., 5-2-61., TLS - 2
    - Cushing, Cardinal Richard (B) to JAH, 5-8-61., TLS - 1
    - Cushing, Cardinal Richard, printed leaflet re seminary -, 8
    - Pierardo[?] (Rome) to Cardinal Cushing, 2-7-61., PLS - 2
    - Clippings re -, 6
    - Press photos of, 1948, 4 w/cov. and invoice
  - D (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - DE LA MARE, WALTER (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - De la Mare, Walter (Penn, Bucks.) to OG, 11-18-42., TLS - 1 w/cov.
  - DENSON, ALAN (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to OG, 10-26-54., ALS - 1
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to OG, 11-24-54, ALS - 1
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to OG, 12-9-54., ALS - 2
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to OG, 12-9-54., ALS - 2
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to OG, 2-26-55., ALS - 1
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to OG, 7-6-55., ALS - 3
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to OG, 7-21-55., ALS - 2
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to OG, 8-17-55., ALS - 3
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to OG, 11-20-55., TLS - 2 w/cov.
      forwarding it to JAH
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to OG, 12-27-55., TLS - 2
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to OG, 12-29-55., TLS - 1
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to OG, 1-11-56., TLS - 1
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to OG, 1-14-56., TLS - 1 enc. copy of letter from Bonamy Dobree to President of Colby College, 1-2-56
    - Denson, Alan (L) to OG, 1-23-56., TLS - 1
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to OG, 3-10-56., TLS - 1 w/cov.
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to Editor, Irish Times, 10-23-54., Clipping - 1
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to JAH, 3-4-55., ALS - 3
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to JAH, 5-16-55., ALS - 3
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to JAH, 12-13-55., ALS - 3
    - Denson, Alan (Kendal) to JAH, 12-29-55., TL - 1
  - DE VALERA, EAMON (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - [De Valera, re] G.A. Wahlen (NYC) to JAH, tele. - 1
    - [De Valera, re] Dinner invitation to meet, PD - 1
    - Clipping re
  - DE VERE, AUBREY (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - De Vere, Aubrey (NP) to Norton, 6-25-1874., ALS - 4
  - DIGGES, DUDLEY AND MARY (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Digges, Dudley (Beverly Hills) to RC, 8-13-35., Trans: TLc - 4 (5)
    - Digges, Dudley (NYC) to JAH, 4-6-37., ALS - 1
    - Digges, Dudley (NYC) to JAH, 4-27-37., TLS - 1
    - Digges, Dudley (NYC) to JAH, 6-17-38., ALS - 1 w/cov.
    - Digges, Dudley (NYC) to JAH, 6-26-38., TLS - 1
    - Digges, Dudley (NYC) to JAH, 7-12-40., ALS - 3 w/cov.
    - Digges, Dudley (NYC) to JAH, 7-20-40., ALS - 3 w/cov.
    - Digges, Dudley (NYC) to JAH, 8-30-40., ALS - 4 w/cov.
    - Digges, Dudley to JAH, 1945.Christmas telegram -, 1
    - Digges, Dudley (NYC) to Major [Kinkead], 4-14-37., ALS - 1
    - Digges, Mary R. (NYC) to Mrs. JAH, 9-8-46., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Digges, Dudley and Mary (NP) to [JAH and Mrs. JAH], Christmas cards -, 2 w/covs.
    - [Digges, Dudley], menu for complimentary dinner for, 4-10-?, PDS - 3 w/a
  - DILLON, EILIS (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Dillon, Eilis (Cork) to JAH, 5-14-61., TLS - 1
    - Dillon, Eilis (Ottawa) to JAH, 11-1-61., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Dillon, Eilis (Corraigh) to JAH. Christmas card, signed -, 1 w/cov.
    - Dillon, Eilis (Pittsburgh) to JAH, 10-25-63., ALS - 4 w/cov.
    - Dillon, Eilis (NYC) to JAH, 10-30-65., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Dillon, Eilis (NP) to JAH and Mrs. JAH, Christmas card, signed, 12-9-65
    - Dillon, Eilis (NP), leaflet announcing her lectures, ND
    - Clipping re talk at Colby
  - DILLON, MYLES (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Dillon, Myles [Madison] to [OG], 3-24-44., ALS - 1 w/ flyer
    - Dillon, Myles (Madison) to JAH, 1-24-44., APCS - 1
    - Clipping re
  - DOUGLAS, LORD ALFRED (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Douglas, Alfred (Lewes, Sussex) to Mr. Lyon, 7-21-18., ALS - 4
    - Clipping re Without Apology, 5-9-38 -, 1
  - DOWDEN, EDWARD (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Dowden, Edward (Rathgar) to EAB, 3-26-13., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Dowden, Edward (D) to EAB, 3-28-13., Clipping, ND - 1
    - Dowden, Edward (D) to Mr. Nutt, 5-6-1890., ALS - 1
    - Dowden, Edward (D) to Mr. dear Rolfe, 4-19-1883., ALS - 4
    - Dowden, Edward (D) to My dear Mr. Rolfe, 12-20-1884., ALS - 4
    - Dowden, Edward (D) to Dear Sir, 3-3-1882., ALS - 2
    - Dowden, Edward (D) to Dear Sir, 10-17-1902., ALS - 4
    - Dowden, Edward (D) to Dear Sir, 12-5-05., ALS - 4
    - Dowden, Edward (NP) to Dear Sir, 10-5-08., ALS - 1
    - Dowden, Edward (D) to WBY, 10-31-12., ALS - 4
  - DREIER, ETHEL E. (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Dreier, Ethel E. (Brooklyn) to AE, 1-30-28., ALS - 2
  - DUNSANY, LORD (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Dunsany (Dunsany Castle, Co. Meath) to OG, [8]26-29]., ALS - 3 w/cov.
    - D (Shoreham, Kent) to OG, 9-21-[34]., ALS - 3 w/cov. (2)
    - D (Wyoming, N. Y.) to Mr. Koehler, ND., ALS - 1
    - D (Shoreham, Kent) to Mr. Matthews, 9-6-19., ALS - 2
    - D (Dunsany Castle, Co. Meath) to Mr. Munson, 4-14-35., ALS - 2
    - D (Shoreham, Kent) to Mr. Munson, 7-5-35., ALS - 2
    - D (Shoreham, Kent) to Mr. Owlett, 6-24-54., ALS - 4
    - D (Shoreham, Kent) to Mr. Owlett, 7-5-56., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - D (Dunsany Castle, Co. Meath) to [Fraulein Steinbock], 2-19-32.Authorization of translation, ANS - 1
    - D (Shoreham, Kent) to [Wilson] Vance, 6-13-30., ALS - 4 w/cov.
    - D (Shoreham, Kent) to Mr. Vance, [June 1931?]., ALS - 7
    - D (Shoreham, Kent) to Mr. Vance, 2-19-32., ALS - 2
    - D (Shoreham, Kent) to Mr. Vance, 6-29-33., ALS - 4
    - D, poem, When the Assault was Intended to the City. A Sonnet Pinned by a Colonel to the Door of his Barracks, ND., ADS - 1 (2)
    - D, poem, To AE, ND. In Lady Dunsany's holograph., Pc of AD - 1 (3)
    - D, poem, The Lost Poet, ND. In Lady Dunsany's holograph., Pc of AD - 1 (3)
    - D, poem, In Memory of AE, ND. In Lady Dunsany's holograph., Pc of AD - 1 (4)
    - Dunsany, [Lady] B. (Shoreham, Kent), to Mr. Humphry, 1-25-57., Trans.: TL - 1
  - E (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - ELY, R.E. (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Ely, R.E. (NYC) to AE, 1-27-28., TLS - 1
  - ERVINE, ST. JOHN (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Ervine, St. John (L) to EAB, 8-3-25., ALS - 2 w/cov.
  - F (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - FARRELL, PATRIC (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Farrell, Patric (NYC) to RC, 3-7-33., TLS - 1
    - Farrell, Patric (NYC) to RC, 11-23-33., TLS - 1
    - Farrell, Patric (Bethel, Conn.) to JAH, [9-24-46]., APCS - 1
    - Clippings re -, 3
  - FAY, F. J. AND W. G. (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Fay, F. J. (Swansea) to M. Bourgeois, ND., ALS - 4
    - Fay, F. J. (Warrington) to Dear Sir [probably M. Bourgeois], ND., ALS - 4
    - Fay, William G. (Highgate) to M. Bourgeois, ND., ALS - 1
    - Fay, William G. (L) to M. Bourgeois, 6-11-11., APCS - 1
    - Fay, William G. (Highgate) to M. Bourgeois, 5-4-13., ALS - 1
    - Fay, William G. ([L]) to M. Bourgeois, [November 1912]., APCS - 1
    - Fay, William G. (L) to M. Bourgeois, 7-22-13., APCS - 1
  - FIGGIS, DARRELL (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Figgis, Darrell (Hampstead Garden) to M. Bourgeois, 8-20-11., ALS - 1
    - Figgis, Darrell (Hampstead Garden) to M. Bourgeois, 9-3-11., ALS - 1
    - Figgis, Darrell (Hampstead Garden) to M. Bourgeois, 3-30-12., ALS - 1
    - Figgis, Darrell (Durham Prison) to EAB, 8-30-18., ALS - 3
    - Figgis, Darrell (Durham Jail) to EAB, 9-11-18., ALS - 1
    - Figgis, Darrell ([L]) to EAB, 12-1-18., APCS - 1
    - Figgis, Darrell (Durham Jail) to EAB, 12-12-18., ALS - 1
    - Figgis, Darrell (Durham Jail) to EAB, 12-19-18., ALS - 1
    - Figgis, Darrell (D) to My dear Lyon[?], 5-17-18., ALS - 1
    - Clipping re, Death of Dublin Girl, Irish Times, ND
    - Clipping re death of, Weekly Irish Times, 1925
    - Clipping re death of, 10-27-[25]
    - Clipping re death of, Sunday News, 11-1-25
  - FOX, CHARLOTTE MILLIGAN (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Fox, C.M. (Kenley, Surrey) to [F.A.] King, 7-9-13., ALS - 6
    - Fox, C.M. (NYC) to [F.A.] King, ND., ALS - 3 enc.
      flyer for her book The Annals of the Irish Harpers
    - Fox, C.M. (NYC) to [F.A.] King, Thursday., ALS - 4
    - Fox, C.M. (NP), script for lecture, Irish Dirges and Elegies, ND., TDS - 7
      w/ annotated page of music and words for Donaghy Bau - 1; and pasted photograph entitled A Mourner - 1
    - Fox, C.M. (NP) lecture, Rural Poets and Singers of Ireland, ND., TD
      w/ AMS titlepage; tearsheet of printed sketch; and words and music for Red Salmon
  - FOX, R.M. (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Fox, R.M. (D) to JAH, 7-10-48., ALS - 3 w/cov.
      and flyer for his Years of Freedom
    - Fox, R.M. (D) to JAH, 8-6-48., ALS - 4 w/cov.
    - Fox, R.M. (D) to JAH, 9-11-48., ALS - 4
  - G (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - GALLAGHER, FRANK [PSEUD. DAVID HOGAN] (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Gallagher, Frank (Sutton, Co. Dublin) to JAH, 6-3-58., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Gallagher, Frank (Sutton, Co. Dublin) to JAH, 7-6-59., ALS - 3
    - Gallagher, Frank (Sutton, Co. Dublin) to JAH, 5-14-61, ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Clipping re: review of his The Anglo-Irish Treaty, by F.MacManus
  - GALLAGHER, J.J. (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Gallagher, J.J. (NYC) to JAH, 4-2-43., ALS - 1
    - Gallagher, J.J. (NYC) to Patrick MacCartan, 7-16-37., TLc - 1
    - Gallagher, J.J. (NP) to [OG], 10-22-[35]., Trans: TL - 2 (1)
    - Gallagher, J.J. (NP) to M.L. Wilson, ND[UNK], Trans: Atele - 1
  - GARMAN, A.A. (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Garman, A. A. (Canisteo) to OG, 3-20-50., ALS - 1
  - GIBBON, MONK (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Gibbon, Monk (Swanage) to Seamus O'Sullivan, 10-22-37., ALS - 6
    - Gibbon, Monk (NP) to Seamus O'Sullivan, 10-23-37., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Gibbon, Monk (Swanage) to Seamus O'Sullivan, 11-11-37., ALS - 2
    - Gibbon, Monk (Donegal) to Seamus O'Sullivan, 4-22-47., ALS - 2 w/cov.
  - GIBSON, HUGH (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - [UNK], Hugh (NYC) to OG, 3-16-43., TLS - 1
  - GOGARTY, OLIVER D. (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - Gogarty, Oliver D. (D) to JAH, 4-7-60., TLS - 2 w/cov.
    - Gogarty, Oliver D. (D) to JAH, 8-16-64., ALS - 2
    - Gogarty, Oliver D. (D) to JAH, 8-22-64., ALS - 5
    - Gogarty, Oliver D. (D) to JAH, 5-5-60., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Gogarty, Oliver D. (D) to JAH, 5-14-60., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Gogarty, Oliver D. (D) to JAH, 5-31-60., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Gogarty, Oliver D. (D) to JAH, 3-28-63., ALS - 4
  - OLIVER ST. JOHN GOGARTY TO BASSETT; BOYD (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - [OG] (NP) to [John Bassett], ND., AL draft w/cov (unsent) enc. 2 clippings
    - OG (D) to EAB, 10-18-22., TLS w/a - 3 w/cov. [includes text of poem Earth and Sea)
    - OG (D) to EAB, 6-15-23., TLS w/a - 2
    - OG (D) to EAB, 1-24-24., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (D) to EAB, 2-14-24., TLS w/a - 2
    - OG (D) to EAB, 4-2-24., ALS - 2
    - OG (NP) to EAB, 2-3-25., ALS - 4
  - GOGARTY, OLIVER ST. JOHN, TO RICHARD CAMPBELL (Box 6, Folder 85)
    - OG (D) to RC, 9-10-29., ALS - 4
    - OG (D) to RC, 1-11-30., ALS - 4
    - OG (D) to RC, 1-27-30., ALS - 6
    - OG (D) to RC, 2-13-30., ALS - 4
    - OG (D) to RC, 3-13-30., ALS - 4, plus postscript AL - 1
    - OG (D) to RC, 4-6-30., ALS - 1
    - OG (D) to RC, 7-23-30., ALS - 4
    - OG (D) to RC, 9-27-30., ALS - 4
    - OG (D) to RC, [ca. Oct? 1930]., ALS - 7
    - OG (NP) to RC, 2-24-31., TLS - 3
    - OG (D) to RC, 8-15-31., ALS - 2
    - OG (D) to RC, 10-5-31., TLS - 4
    - OG (D) to RC, 11-16-31., TLS w/a - 5
    - OG (D) to RC, 12-5-31., TLS - 6
    - OG (D) to RC, 1-14-32., TLS - 10
    - OG (D) to RC, ND [1932?]., TLS - 4
    - OG (D) to RC, 2-12-32., TLS - 7
    - OG (D) to RC, 3-6-32., TLS - 6
    - OG (D) to RC, 5-9-32., TLS - 2
    - OG (D) to RC, 5-21-32., TLS - 13
    - OG (D) to RC, 8-24-32., TLS w/a - 10
    - OG (D) to RC, 10-15-32., TLS w/a - 6
    - OG (D) to RC, 12-3-32., TLS - 4
    - OG (Pittsburgh) to RC, 1-23-33., ALS - 1
    - OG (D) to RC, 4-2-33., TLS w/a - 2
    - OG (D) to RC, 4-30-33., TLS w/a - 2
    - OG (D) to RC, 5-10-33., TLS - 4
    - OG (D) to RC, [5-11?-33].clipping of OG to [Editor of Irish Times?], (D), [ca. May 1933], Irish Authors, Beware, TLS w/a - 2, enc.
    - OG (D) to RC, 5-12-33., TLS - 2
    - OG (NP) to RC, [mid-1933]., TLS - 2
    - OG (D) to RC, 10-3-33., TL - 3
    - OG (D) to RC, 10-9-33., TLS w/a - 2
    - OG (D) to RC, 11-13-33., TL w/a - 2
    - OG (D) to RC, 11-30-33., TLS w/a - 1
    - OG (D) to RC, 12-18-33., TL - 2
    - OG (Galway) to RC, 12-25-33., ALS - 2
    - OG (D) to RC, 1-16-34., TLS - 2
    - OG (D) to RC, 2-12-34., TLS w/a - 5
    - OG (D) to RC, 2-27-34., TLS w/a - 4
    - OG (D) to RC, 4-5-34., TLS w/a - 5
    - OG (D) to RC, 6-16-34., ALS - 2
    - OG (D) to RC, 6-17-34., TLS - 2
    - OG (Galway) to RC, 9-24-34., TLS - 2
    - OG (D) to RC, 12-1-34., TLS - 6
    - OG (NP) to RC, 1-15-35., TLS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (D) to RC, 1-22-35., Tele - 1
    - OG (D) to RC, 3-14-35., TLS - 2
    - OG (D) to RC, 3-30-35., TLS - 2
    - OG (D) to RC, 8-28-35., TLS w/a - 3
    - OG (D) to RC, [10-5-35]., TLS w/a - 2 w/cov. and trans.
  - GOGARTY, OLIVER St. JOHN TO JOHN J. GALLAGHER (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - OG (D) to J. J. Gallagher, 11-9-35., TLS w/a - 1
    - OG (D) to J. J. Gallgher, 8-2-36., ALS - 2 and 2 trans.
    - OG (D) to J. J. Gallagher, 10-24-36., ALS - 2 and 2 trans.
    - OG (D) to J. J. Gallagher, 11-17-36., ALS - 2 w/cov. and 2 trans.
    - OG (NYC) to J. J. Gallagher, 1-4-40., ALS - 1
    - OG (NYC) to J. J. Gallagher, 12-20-45., TLS - 1
  - GOGARTY, OLIVER ST. JOHN, TO JAMES A. HEALY, 1937-43 (Box 6, Folder 87)
    - OG (D) to JAH, 2-27-37., TLS - 4 w/cov.
    - OG (D) to JAH, 2-29-37., ALS - 1
    - OG (D) to JAH, 3-4-37., ALS written on a CP flyer for The New Broadsides - 3 w/cov.
    - OG (D) to JAH, 3-8-37., ALS - 2
    - OG (D) to JAH, 12-1-37., TLS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (D) to JAH, 6-22-38., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (Renvyle, Galway) to JAH, 8-27-38., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (NP) to JAH, 11-1-38., ALS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (Baileatha Cliath) to JAH, Nov. 1938., 2 empty covers
    - OG (Rènvyle, Galway) to JAH, 12-7-38., TLS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (Cambridge, Mass.) to JAH, 10-8-39., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 10-12-39., ALS - 3 w/cov.
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, [3-5-40]., ALS - 3 w/cov.
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 3-29-40., TLS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 5-19-40., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (New Jersey) to JAH, 3-28-41., ALS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (New Jersey) to JAH, 4-19-41., TLS 2 w/cov.
    - OG (New Jersey) to JAH, 4-26-41., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (Wisconsin) to JAH, 4-30-41., ALS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (New Jersey) to JAH, 5-6-41., TLS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (New Jersey) to JAH, 5-14-41., TLS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG [NYC] to JAH, 7-14-41., ALS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (NP) to JAH, 7-14-41., ALS - 1
    - OG (Maine) to JAH [7-28-41]., ANS - 1
    - OG (New Jersey) to JAH, 8-4-[41]., ALS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, [12-4-41]., APCS w/cov.
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 12-8-41., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (NP) to JAH, 2-3-42., TLS - 1 enc.
      E.L. Macassey to OG, 1-3-42, now filed under M
    - OG (NP) to JAH, 2-11-42., ANS - 1 w/ 2 empty covers
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 2-12-42., APCS - 1
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 2-17-42., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (NP) to JAH, 2-22-42., ALS - 1 w/cov.
    - [OG] ([NYC]) to [JAH], [3-17-42]., AN - 1
      on back of penciled phone message for OG
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 3-19-42., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 4-1-42., TPC - 1
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 4-9-42., TPCS - 1
    - OG (NP) to JAH, [4-14-42]., TLS - 1 w/cov., enc.
      typed poem, To a Lady Reviewer
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 5-6-42., TLS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 5-9-42., TLS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 6-4-42., TPCS - 1
    - OG (Manhasset) to JAH, 6-24-42., TLS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (St. Alban's) to JAH, 7-9-42., ALS - 1
    - OG (NP) to JAH, 7-20-42., ALS - 2
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 8-14-42., ALS - 4 w/cov.
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 9-21-42., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (NP) to JAH, 10-27-42., ANS - 1 w/cov.
      on same sheet as typed poem To His Friends When His Prostrate Shall Have Become Enlarged
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 12-10-42., ALS - 2, enc.
      autograph poem Remembering Albert Spickers, ADS, 12-5-[42] - 3
    - OG (Vermont) to JAH, 7-16-43., ALS - 4 w/cov., enc.
      poem Galway, AD - 1
    - OG (Vermont) to JAH, 7-24-43., ALS - 3 w/cov.
    - OG (Vermont) to JAH, 7-30-43., TLS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (Vermont) to JAH, 8-5-43., APCS - 1
    - OG (Vermont) to JAH, 8-10-43., TL - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (Vermont) to JAH, 8-18-43., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (The Drain) to JAH, 10-1-43., TLS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 10-22-4., TPCS - 1
    - Clippings, New Film Location Sought in Erie, To Show Ireland As It is -, 2
  - GOGARTY, OLIVER ST. JOHN, TO HEALY, 1944-56 (Box 6, Folder 88)
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 1-26-44., TLS w/a - 1 w/cov., enc.
      poem, The Airman's Breastplate, TDS w/a - 1
    - [OG] (NP) [2-7-44].Draft of statement supporting his application for a permit to practice as a doctor in the U.S. -, AD - 6
    - OG (NP) to JAH, [3-6-44]., ALS - 2 [second page is autograph poem, Song] w/cov.
    - OG (Chicago) to JAH, 3-11-44., ALS - 2 w/cov., enc.
      clipping The House of Macmillan
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 3-23-44., TNS w/cov., enc.
      clipping, Midwest
    - OG (NP) to JAH, 3-24-44., TNS - 1
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, [3-26-44]., TNS - 1 w/cov., enc.
      poem, The Pilot's Breastplate [same as The Airman's Breastplate] TD - 1
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, [3-29-44]., Empty cover
    - OG (Maryland) to JAH, 4-10-44., APCS - 1
    - OG (NP) to JAH, [after 4-10-44]., ANS - 1 [written at bottom of Shirley Collier (Beverly Hills) to OG, TLS - 1]
    - OG (Maryland) to JAH, 4-17-44., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (Maryland) to JAH, 4-19-44., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (Maryland) to JAH, 5-3-44., TLS w/a - 2
    - OG (Maryland) to JAH, 5-3-44., TLS w/a - 2 w/cov. postmarked 5-2-44, enc.
      3 clippings (one by Seamus O'Sullivan)
    - OG (Maryland) to JAH, 5-10-44., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (Maryland) to JAH, 5-10-44., APCS - 1
    - OG (Maryland) to JAH, 5-22-44., TLS - 4 w/a, w/cov.
    - OG (Vermont) to JAH, 6-20-44., TNS w/a - 1 enc. AN - 1
    - OG (Vermont) to JAH, 6-26-44., TLS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (Vermont) to JAH, 6-27-44., TLS - 1 w/cov., enc.
      Washington Post voucher, 6-15-44
    - OG (Vermont) to JAH, 6-29-44., TLS w/a - 2
    - OG (Vermont) to JAH, 7-13-44., TLS w/a - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (Vermont) to JAH, 8-2-44., TLS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (New Jersey) to JAH, 11-15-44., APCS - 1
    - OG (New Jersey) to JAH, 12-21-44., APCS - 1
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, Christmas 1944., ANS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG ([NYC]) to JAH, 1-31-45., TLS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (NP) to JAH, 9-23-45., TLS - 2 (3)
    - OG (Maryland) to JAH, 5-3-46., APCS - 1
    - OG (Maryland) to JAH, 5-22-46., TLS w/a - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (Offaly) to JAH, Whitmonday [received 5-29-47]., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (Galway) to [JAH], 6-17-47., APCS - 1
      (depicts Renvyle House Hotel)
    - OG (Galway) to JAH, 7-1-47., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (Galway) to JAH, 8-4-47., TLS w/a - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (NP), fragment of blurb for I Follow St. Patrick, ND., AD - 2
    - OG (NP) to JAH, [12-21-47]., TLS - 1 w/cov. (includes typed proposal for I Follow St. Patrick as a movie)
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 1-9-48., TLS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (NP), airline insurance policy, 1-25-48., PDS w/a - 2
    - OG (NP) to JAH, 2-24-48., TLS - 1
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 7-22-48., APCS - 1
    - OG (NYC) to JAH, 3-8-49., TLS w/a - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (Eire) to JAH, 6-15-49., APCS - 1
    - OG (Galway) to JAH, 6-27-49., TLS - 2
    - OG (Galway) to JAH, 6-29-49., TLS - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (Galway) to JAH, 7-24-49., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - OG (Galway) to JAH, 8-11-49., APCS - 1
    - OG (Galway) to JAH, 9-9-49., TLS - 1 enc.
      2 poems: 1) Strong men are they who guide their ships, TD w/a and TNS - 1; 2) On the Sale of St. Nicholas's Church, TD - 1 w/cov.
    - OG (Galway) to JAH, 5-10-50., APCS with poem on Limerick - 1
    - OG (NP) to JAH, 6-25-50., TLS - 1 [enc.
      letters from LG, GY, and O'Casey, now placed in their appropriate folders]
    - OG to JAH, 1950., 2 empty envelopes